John A. Lomax and Alan Lomax papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series I: Correspondence, 1925-1952 and undated
  - Subseries III: Alan Lomax, 1935-1969 and undated (Box-folder 3/115)
    - November 1938 (Box-folder 4/139)
      - Joseph Arnstein to Alan Lomax, 1938-11-29
        Chicago Board of Education
    - December 1938 (Box-folder 4/140)
      - Mildred Stocker to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-01
      - John O. Walker to Harold Spivacke, 1938-12-02
        Farm Security Administration
      - Herbert Putnam to Frederick P. Keppel, 1938-12-02
        Carnegie Corporation of New York; likely a draft not sent
      - Alan Lomax to Mildred Stocker, 1938-12-03
      - Herbert Putnam to Frederick P. Keppel, 1938-12-03
        Carnegie Corporation of New York; includes letter to Keppel (5 copies) report about the archive dated 1938-11-19 proposing personnel changes (2 copies, one incomplete)
      - Felix Greene to Charles B. Elam, 1938-12-04
      - Nonie Collett to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-04
      - Alan Lomax to Martina McDonald, 1938-12-05
        Typed and handwritten copies
      - Harold Spivacke to John O. Walker, 1938-12-05
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-06
      - Alan Lomax to D.G. Rowse, 1938-12-08
      - Alan Lomax to John M. Umble, 1938-12-08
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Beck, 1938-12-08
        Central State Teachers College (Michigan); Michigan 1938 recording trip; photocopy
      - Alan Lomax to John Hammond, 1938-12-08
      - Frederick P. Keppel to Herbert Putnam, 1938-12-08
        2 copies
      - Alan Lomax to Florence Dean Stryker, 1938-12-09
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1938-12-09
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Krimsky, 1938-12-09
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-09
        Goshen College (Indiana); date not certain
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1938-12-09
        Michigan 1938 recording trip; duplication of recordings, see also 1938-12-14 memo
      - Paul A. Unger to Lt. Col. Brehon B. Somervell, 1938-12-09
        Works Progress Administration; New York World's Fair
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1938-12-09
      - Martina McDonald to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-10
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-12
      - John Shawbitz to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-12
      - D.G. Rowse to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-12
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-12
        Central State Teachers College (Michigan); Michigan 1938 recording trip
      - Mildred Stocker to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-13
      - Ruth R. Roark to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-13
      - Alistair Cooke to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-14
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1938-12-14
        duplication of recordings, see also 1938-12-14
      - Alan Lomax to John Shawbitz, 1938-12-20
      - Alan Lomax to John M. Umble, 1938-12-20
      - Alan Lomax to Esther Bell Beachy, 1938-12-21
      - Alan Lomax to Library of Congress Music Division, 1938-12-21
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Beck, 1938-12-21
      - Alan Lomax to Mrs. J.K. Beachy, 1938-12-21
      - Alan Lomax to Joseph Arnstein, 1938-12-27
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Mail Division, 1938-12-30
      - Stephen W. Smith to Alan Lomax, 1938-12-30
        Hot Record Society
    - January 1939 (Box-folder 4/141)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-01-04
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-06
        Goshen College (Indiana); 1938 typed, but likely mistaken
      - Stephen Lewandowski to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-09
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-01-13
      - Alan Lomax to Stephen W. Smith, 1939-01-14
      - Alan Lomax to Nonie Collett, 1939-01-17
        Farmer Collett
      - Alan Lomax to Ruth R. Roark, 1939-01-17
      - Alan Lomax to John M. Umble, 1939-01-17
      - Mrs. Vernon Rautanen to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-18
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1939-01-19
      - Nonie Collett to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-20
      - Metropolitan Sound Co. to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-20
        Metropolitan Sound Co.; Michigan 1938 recording trip equipment
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-21
      - Alan Lomax to Metropolitan Sound Co., 1939-01-24
      - Olive Beaupre Miller to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-25
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Mail Division, 1939-01-27
      - Felix Greene to Alan Lomax, 1939-01-31
      - Felix Greene to John A. Lomax, 1939-01-31
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, circa 1939
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, circa 1939
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, circa 1939
    - February 1939 (Box-folder 4/142)
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Disbursing Office, 1939-02-02
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-03
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-08
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-02-08
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02-08
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-02-08
      - Edward N. Waters to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-10
      - Frances Perkins to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-11
        U.S. Department of Labor
      - Richard Leekley to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-11
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02-16
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-16
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-17
      - Harold Spivacke to Mortimer Graves, 1939-02-20
        American Council of Learned Societies
      - Paul R. Hanna to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-20
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-24
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02-24
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02-26
      - Frances Perkins to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-27
      - Frances Perkins to Alan Lomax, 1939-02-27
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-02
    - March 1939 (Box-folder 4/143)
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-01
      - Alex J. Reben to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-10
        Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter bail bond
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-14
      - Alan Lomax to John M. Umble, 1939-03-16
      - Len Frank to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-16
        Carnegie Hall Recording Co.
      - Alan Lomax to Paul R. Hanna, 1939-03-17
      - Henry Cohen to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-17
        Musicraft Records, Inc.
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-03-20
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-21
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-21
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-03-21
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-21
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-22
      - Paul R. Hanna to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-23
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-03-26
        mentions Robert Johnson
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-03-31
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-03-31
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-03
        undated
    - April 1939 (Box-folder 4/144)
      - Harold Spivacke to John M. Umble, 1939-04-01
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-04-04
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-04-08
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-04-14
      - Edward N. Waters to Alan Lomax, 1939-04-17
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-04-17
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Chief Clerk, 1939-04-18
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-04-22
    - May 1939 (Box-folder 4/145)
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-01
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-03
      - Benjamin A. Botkin to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-11
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-13
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-13
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-16
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-16
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-20
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-25
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-05-28
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-05-29
    - June 1939 (Box-folder 4/146)
      - E.C. Forman to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-01
      - John M. Umble to Alan Lomax, 1939-06-01
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-06-01
        White House performance
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1939-06-01
      - Harold Spivacke to E.C. Forman, 1939-06-05
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Charles Engel, 1939-06-07
      - Alan Lomax to Mortimer Graves, 1939-06-09
      - Harold Spivacke to Davidson Taylor, 1939-06-09
      - Harold Spivacke to E.C. Forman, 1939-06-12
      - Harold Spivacke to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-06-12
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-06-12
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-13
      - Library of Congress Chief Assistant Librarian to Wallace D. Brock, 1939-06-14
      - E.C. Forman to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-14
      - David Spaziani to Alan Lomax, 1939-06-14
      - Harold Spivacke to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-06-15
      - Alan Lomax to Davidson Taylor, 1939-06-16
      - Library of Congress Chief Assistant Librarian to Wallace D. Brock, 1939-06-17
      - Library of Congress Office of the Librarian to Library of Congress Disbursing Office, 1939-06-17
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-20
      - Harold Spivacke to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-06-21
      - Sarah Buchanan Salles to Alan Lomax, 1939-06-22
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Chief Clerk, 1939-06-23
      - Ben Robertson to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-26
      - Harold Spivacke to E.C. Forman, 1939-06-27
      - E.C. Forman to Harold Spivacke, 1939-06-29
    - July 1939 (Box-folder 5/147)
      - Harold Spivacke to E.C. Forman, 1939-07-05
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Mail Division, 1939-07-06
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Harold Spivacke, 1939-07-07
      - Harold Spivacke to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-07-08
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Beck, 1939-07-17
      - Alan Lomax to David Spaziani, 1939-07-18
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1939-07-20
      - John Hammond to Alan Lomax, 1939-07-25
    - August 1939 (Box-folder 5/148)
      - Alan Lomax to Library of Congress Accessions, 1939-08-05
      - Alan Lomax to John Hammond, 1939-08-08
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Mail Division, 1939-08-10
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Mail Division, 1939-08-11
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-08-16
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1939-08-17
      - David C. Mearns to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-19
      - Alan Lomax to Beal D. Taylor, 1939-08-21
      - Marjorie Sanborn to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-21
      - Alan Lomax to Richard Allen, 1939-08-24
        Indiana University
      - John Hammond to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-25
      - Robert Van Zant to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-26
      - Sterling Fisher to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-28
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1939-08-29
      - Alan Lomax to Marjorie Sanborn, 1939-08
      - Library of Congress Publications Office to Alan Lomax, 1939-08
        Annual report formatting
    - September 1939 (Box-folder 5/149)
      - Charles to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-02
      - Alan Lomax to Paul G. Brewster, 1939-09-02
        University of Missouri, Columbia
      - Regers, Muriel to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-03
      - Alan Lomax to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-09-08
      - Alan Lomax to Muriel Regers, 1939-09-08
      - Stanton H. King to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-12
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-13
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-14
      - Alan Lomax to Stanton H. King, 1939-09-14
      - Barrow Lyons to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-14
        Securities and Exchange Commission
      - Alan Lomax to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-09-15
      - Unidentified to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-16
      - Nelson Sprackling to John A. Lomax, 1939-09-16
      - Paul G. Brewster to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-16
      - Alan Lomax to Nelson Sprackling, 1939-09-18
      - Stanton H. King to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-20
      - Alan Lomax to Wellnew Motors, 1939-09-20
        See also 1939-12-21; 1941-01-11
      - Alan Lomax to Paul G. Brewster, 1939-09-25
      - Alan Lomax to Cornel Lengyel, 1939-09-26
        See also 1939-10-17; 1939-10-19
      - Homer P. Rainey to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-27
      - Nelson Sprackling to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-29
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1939-09-29
    - October 1939 (Box-folder 5/150)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-10-02
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-03
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-03
      - Moses Smith to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-03
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Beck, 1939-10-04
        Central State Teachers College (Michigan); reply attached
      - Moses Smith to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-11
      - E.C. Beck to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-11
      - William H. Fineschriber to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-11
      - Alan Lomax to Peter Stammer, 1939-10-13
      - Alan Lomax to E.C. Beck, 1939-10-13
      - Alan Lomax to George Lutman, 1939-10-13
      - Alan Lomax to Julias Mattfeld, 1939-10-13
      - Alan Lomax to Phillip King, 1939-10-15
        Maritime Commission
      - Alan Lomax to Torrent, Lewis, Paddy Miles, Bill Duchaine, 1939-10-18
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-23
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-10-23
      - John D. Kirby to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-24
        Terrill Preparatory School
      - Malcom Ross to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-24
        National Labor Relations Board
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-25
        Annual report
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-10-26
      - Harry Robin to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-26
        University of Minnesota
      - Evans Clark to Alan Lomax, 1939-10-30
        The Twentieth Century Fund
      - Nicholas Ray to Alan Lomax, 1939-10
    - November 1939 (Box-folder 5/151)
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-11-16
        Michigan 1938 recording trip; Vermont 1939
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-01
      - Herbert Halpert to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-02
      - Janet Kromer to Harold Spivacke, 1939-11-13
      - Sheldon Dick to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-15
        Lee Dick Films, Inc.
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-16
      - Alan Lomax to Tony, 1939-11-18
      - Alan Lomax to Sheldon Dick, 1939-11-20
      - Max Kahn to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-20
        Free Synagogue Committee for Refugees
      - Alan Lomax to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-11-20
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-20
      - Edward P. Jennings to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-20
      - Alan Lomax to Edward P. Jennings, 1939-11-21
      - Edward P. Jennings to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-28
      - Sheldon Dick to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-25
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-11-29
      - Alan Lomax to Roy Mitchell 1939-11-29
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-11-29
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-29
      - E.C. Ball to Alan Lomax, 1939-11-29
      - Alan Lomax to David P. Bennett, 1939-11-25
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1939-11-29
        Roy Mitchell
    - December 1939 (Box-folder 5/152)
      - Mrs. E. Mac Nutt to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-01
      - Joanna C. Colcord to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-01
      - Frances McFarland to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-04
        Works Progress Administration, New York City Music Project
      - Alan Lomax to Mrs. E. Mac Nutt, 1939-12-07
      - Alan Lomax to Sheldon Dick, 1939-12-07
      - I.S. Becker to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-07
        Columbia Artists, Inc.
      - Alan Lomax to Joanna C. Colcord, 1939-12-08
      - Alan Lomax to Edward P. Jennings, 1939-12-09
      - Alan Lomax to Allen Eaton, 1939-12-09
        "Bonaparte's Retreat"
      - J. B. Lippincott Co. to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-11
      - Marshall Bartholomew to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-12
        International Student Music Council
      - RCA Manufacturing Co., Inc. to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-14
      - Alan Lomax to RCA Manufacturing Co., Inc., 1939-12-15
      - Alan Lomax to Frank Frazier, 1939-12-15
        J.B. Lippincott Co.
      - Alan Lomax to Columbia Recording Company, 1939-12-15
      - Allen Eaton to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-15
      - Alan Lomax to Alec Saron, 1939-12-16
        Cabaret TAC
      - Alan Lomax to Sterling Fisher, 1939-12-16
      - Alan Lomax to John Hammond, 1939-12-16
      - Alan Lomax to Mrs. John Hough, 1939-12-16
      - Alan Lomax to Glen H. Noyes, 1939-12-16
      - Alan Lomax to Dorothy Dunn Morrison, 1939-12-18
      - Alan Lomax to Allen Eaton, 1939-12-18
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1939-12-19
      - Fisher to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-20
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1939-12-20
      - Alan Lomax to Herbert Robbins, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Robert P. Wetherald, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Marjorie Sanborn, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to I.S. Becker, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Dora Bryant, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to John P. Buchanan, 1939-12-22
      - Alan Lomax to Moses Smith, 1939-12-24
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, undated
      - Dora Bryant to Alan Lomax, 1939-12
      - Eugene Rosen to Tait, 1939-12
        Presto Recording Company
      - Ruby Pickens Tartt to unidentified, 1939-12
        Bing Oliver
    - January 1940 (Box-folder 5/153)
      - Arizona Highways to Alan Lomax, 1940
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1940
        Gordon, Robert W.; undated
      - Alan Lomax to unidentified, 1940
        Christmas list
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-03
      - Alan Lomax to Moses Smith, 1940-01-03
      - Annabel Morris Buchanan to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-03
      - Edward N. Waters to Eugene Rosen, 1940-01-03
      - Alan Lomax to Marshall Bartholomew, 1940-01-04
      - Alan Lomax to General Federation Headquarters, 1940-01-04
        General Federation Headquarters
      - Alan Lomax to M.L. Rein, 1940-01-04
      - Elizabeth Stryker to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-05
      - Alan Lomax to E. Milby Burton, 1940-01-05
        Charleston Museum
      - Mrs. H. F. Wright to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-09
      - Edward N. Waters to Sidney Robertson, 1940-01-11
      - Mayo to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-14
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-16
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-16
      - Harold Spivacke to M.M. Gouger, 1940-01-16
        Western Light & Telephone Co.
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-17
      - M.S. Novik to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-17
      - Mrs. H.G. Landon to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-17
      - Harold Spivacke to Librarian of Congress, 1940-01-24
      - Dan Storm to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-25
      - Mrs. E. M. Langham to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-30
      - Mrs. Chester E. Lamb to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-30
      - Joseph Roy to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-30
      - Mrs. Clark Quick to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-31
      - Mrs. George Hensler to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-31
      - Marjorie Wright to Alan Lomax, 1940-01-31
      - Marie P. to Alan Lomax and Elizabeth Lomax, circa 1940
      - Ross Unger to Alan Lomax, circa 1940
    - February 1940 (Box-folder 5/154)
      - Helen Whitaker to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-01
      - Alan Lomax to Helen Whitaker, 1940-02-01
      - Rose Martinelli to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-02
      - C. L. Cannon to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-03
      - Alan Lomax to Mrs. H. F. Wright, 1940-02-07
      - Alan Lomax to Mrs. H.G. Landon, 1940-02-07
      - Lesley Newton to Archibald MacLeish, 1940-02-07
        American Library Association
      - Margret Shaub to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-08
      - Katherine C. Kilgore to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-09
      - Helen Hartness Flanders to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-12
        Federation of Women's Clubs
      - Arch A. Mercey to Lowell Mellett, 1940-02-14
        Executive Office of the President
      - Edward N. Waters to Library of Congress Music Division, 1940-02-14
        William Graubard
      - Lowell Mellett to Archibald MacLeish, 1940-02-15
      - Harold Spivacke to Archibald MacLeish, 1940-02-17
      - Archibald MacLeish to Lesley Newton, 1940-02-19
      - Augustus D. Zanzig to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-20
      - Isabel R. Scott to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-20
        Columbia Lecture Bureau
      - Columbia Artists, Inc. to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-20
        Columbia Artists, Inc.; contract
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1940-02-21
      - Unidentified to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-22
      - Clarence Cameron White to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-24
        City of Cincinnati, Ohio
      - Ruth K. Webb to Alan Lomax, 1940-02-27
        D.C. Public Schools
    - March 1940 (Box-folder 5/155)
      - William Berrien to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-03
        Conference on Inter-American relations in the Field of Music
      - Pierre Loving to Will Geer, 1940-03-04
        National Youth Administration
      - Donal Henderson to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-04
        UCAPAWA, labor union
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1940-03-04
      - Joanna C. Colcord to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-07
      - Julian Lee Rayford to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-10
      - William George King to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-13
      - W. B. Andrews to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-14
      - Mrs. Samuel J. Brandenburg to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-17
      - Pierre Loving to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-19
      - Alan Lomax to Corrine Brown, 1940-03-19
      - Leon Levine to Corrine Brown, 1940-03-19
      - W.E. Babb to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-20
        Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway Co.
      - William H. Fineschriber to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-21
      - Edward N. Waters to Library of Congress Music Division, 1940-03-21
        Woody Guthrie
      - Mrs. Cosim Brown to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-24
      - Harold Spivacke to Library of Congress Music Division, 1940-03-28
        Alan Lomax travel to AFS
      - Ruth K. Webb to Alan Lomax, 1940-03-30
    - April 1940 (Box-folder 5/156)
      - Clara Brown to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-01
        Corrine Brown
      - Lesley Newton to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-02
      - C.E. Tucker to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-03
      - Joris Ivens to Archibald MacLeish, 1940-04-04
        Joseph Losey
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-04
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-05
      - Francis Waring Robinson to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-07
        Detroit Institute of Arts
      - Lesley Newton to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-08
      - Harold Spivacke to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-10
      - Ivan Walton to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-10
        University of Michigan
      - J. M. Winterbottham to John A. Lomax, 1940-04-11
        Forwarded with note to Alan Lomax
      - Hilder Cole to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-15
        Fred Waring's Pennsylvanians
      - Lesley Newton to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-15
      - Margaret J. Brandenburg to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-16
        Worcester Womens' Club (Massachusetts)
      - Helen Hartness Flanders to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-16
      - Mrs. Whitelaw Stryker to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-16
      - Janet E. Pattison to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-17
      - J. Olcutt Sanders to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-19
      - Mrs. C. Paul Heavener to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-20
        City of Charleston, West Virginia
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-23
      - Isabel R. Scott to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-24
      - Mrs. B. Jones to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-25
      - Joseph Howell to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-27
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-29
      - E.O. Holland to Archibald MacLeish, 1940-04-29
        State College of Washington
      - Ruth K. Webb to Alan Lomax, 1940-04-30
      - Alan Lomax to Harold Spivacke, 1940-04
    - May 1940 (Box-folder 5/157)
      - Joseph Losey to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-01
      - Harold Spivacke to E.O. Holland, 1940-05-02
      - Alan Lomax to E.E. Tucker, 1940-05-06
      - Helen Hartness Flanders to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-06
      - N. R. Augustine to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-06
        Morris Plan Bank of Washington
      - Archibald MacLeish to E.O. Holland, 1940-05-06
      - Robert P. Wetherald to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-07
      - H.C. Darnell to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-08
      - H. M. Schweiger to Alan Lomax, 1940-05-09